Edward King

Pre-Service Teacher

e: ed.king4967@gmail.com m: +1(970)412-0000 w: edkingportfolio.weebly.com/

Personal Profile

I am a motivated, well-rounded, patient individual who never stops learning. Currently student teaching and completing a master's in education at Colorado State University. In undergrad, I earned a bachelor's in English and a minor in Electrical Engineering. Outside the classroom, I worked on a student satellite and a project in Peru that worked to bring education equity to rural populations. Since then, I have worked as an English as a Foreign Language teacher in China and Spain, and as a substitute teacher and tutor in Fort Collins. Throughout, I have continued to build my core skills as a teacher.

Teaching Experience

Student Teacher at Polaris Expeditionary School

September 2020-present. Fort Collins, Colorado.

Student teaching in English as well as Film and American Humanities class.

Private Tutor

October 2020-December 2020. Fort Collins, Colorado.

Tutored all subjects for elementary-age students through remote learning.

Tutor at Huntington Learning Center

June 2019-January 2021. Fort Collins, Colorado.

Tutored for ACT and SAT prep and physics subject tutoring for high school-age students.

Substitute teacher at Poudre School District

August 2018-January 2020. Fort Collins, Colorado.

Substitute-taught a variety of subjects to middle and high school students.

Substitute teacher at Global Village Academy

Fall 2018-Spring 2019. Fort Collins, Colorado.

Taught English and math to kindergarten through 3rd grade students.

English assistant teacher at San Agustin Secondary School

August 2017 - November 2017. San Agustin, Community of Madrid, Spain.

Assistant-taught English as a second language in a Spanish classroom.

High school English teacher at Suzhou Foreign Language School

August 2015 - July 2016. Suzhou, China.

Full time position teaching reading and writing skills in a foreign language high school to prepare students for Western universities.

English teacher at Capable Teams Summer Camp

June-July, 2015. Suzhou and Guangzhou, China.

Taught English activities to students ages 7-9 at Capable Teens Camp (全能少年).

STEM teacher at TEAMS

2009-2010. University of Colorado Boulder, Colorado.

Taught after school STEM activities to students ages 6-12 through TEAMS (Today's Engineers Create Imagine Succeed) program.

Research Experience

Field Interviewer at NapoNet

Boulder, Colorado and Loreto, Peru. June 2011-June 2012

- Traveled to Peru to conduct interviews and community outreach for a telecommunications network.
- Conducted interviews in English and Spanish to assess the use and viability of the network for educational use.
- Assisted in the upkeep of a United Nations-commissioned wireless network.
- Worked on grants, including UROP and NSF, to fund the project.

Education

Colorado State University

Master's in Education. Fort Collins, Colorado.

- Studying education in the CSU's M.Ed. plus Teacher Licensure program.
- Earned a 4.0 GPA on undergraduate pre-rec and master's classes.

University of Colorado

Fall 2009-Spring 2014. Boulder, Colorado.

- Studied English with a focus in creative writing.
- Minored in Electrical Engineering.
- Short story "Fireworks" published in the University of Colorado Honors Journal.
- 3.6 GPA.

Xi'an Jiaotong University

Spring 2012. Xi'an, China.

Completed a one semester Chinese language course.

Volunteer Experience

Volunteer at Immigrant & Refugee Center of Northern Colorado

August-December 2018. Greeley, Colorado.

Worked in an classroom teaching English reading, writing, and speaking skills to primarily Somali refugees and immigrants.

Other Work Experience

Web developer at In-Situ

October 2016-May 2017 Fort Collins, Colorado.

Worked on a web application to aggregate water quality data.

Firmware Engineer at NetApp

August 2014 - July 2015. Boulder, Colorado.

Worked on a cloud backup solution for NetApp's large storage systems.

Residential Advisor at the University of Colorado

Fall 2012-Spring 2013. Boulder, Colorado.

Worked as a residential advisor in Darley Hall, acting as a leader and coordinating activities among a group of incoming students.

Electrical Power Systems team member at University of Colorado Space Grant October 2009 - June 2011. Boulder, Colorado.

Worked on the power system of a research satellite to measure atmosphere composition at lower Earth orbit.

Intern at Hewlett Packard, Fort Collins

Summer, 2008. Fort Collins, Colorado.

Worked in HP's open source lab, learning various open source tools.